http://www.sbctc.ctc.edu/privacy.aspx

Privacy Policy
Thank you for visiting the Washington State Board for Community and Technical College
(SBCTC) website. Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy,
we've developed this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices
you can make about the way your information is collected and used within our sites
and services.
SBCTC reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time without
notice by posting such revised Privacy Notice at the SBCTC home page.
Contact Us
To request correction of factual errors in your personally identifiable information,
offer comments about the SBCTC website or about the information in this Privacy Notice,
contact SBCTC:
Washington State Board for Community and Technical CollegesATTN: WebmasterPO Box 42495Olympia, WA 98504-2495
Phone: 360-704-4400
Email: webmaster@sbctc.edu
Expand All
Information Collected and How it is Used
If you do nothing during your visit except to browse or download information, we automatically
collect and store the following information about your visit:
The internet Protocol Address and domain name is used, but not the email address.
The internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your internet
service provider or directly to your computer. We use the internet Protocol Address
to direct internet traffic to you;
The type of browser and operating system you used;
The date and time you visited this site;
The web pages or services you accessed at this site, and;
Information is collected for site management and summary statistical purposes. This
is used for such purposes as evaluating determining technical design specifications
and identifying system performance or problem areas.
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all
users, SBCTC-supported computer systems employ software programs to monitor network
traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise
cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations and the security
purposes mentioned elsewhere in this notice, no other attempts are made to identify
individual users or their usage habits. Base data logs are used for no other purposes
and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with public records retention
schedules (Chapter 40.14 RCW).
Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service
are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the state Computer Trespass law
(RCW 9A.52.110) and federal statutes including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of
1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.
If you send an email during your visit to the SBCTC website, the server may retain
the email message and email address. We use your email address to respond appropriately
to your request. This may be to address issues you identify, to further improve our
website, or to forward the email for appropriate action.
The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include attachments
such as documents, audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. The
information is retained in accordance with Chapter 40.14 RCW, Preservation and Destruction
of Public Records.
Website Information and Digital Advertising
On occasion, we may work with third parties using cookies, web beacons, and similar
technologies to collect or receive information from this website, its related social
media, and associated web applications and use that information to provide measurement
services and targeted ads. This helps us promote our website and programs to those
who have already shown an interest. You may opt out of this collection and use of
information for ad targeting at any time. Learn more at Understanding Online Advertising.
Personal Information and Choice
"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable
to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name,
address, and phone number. A domain name or internet Protocol address is not considered
personal information.
We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in
an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an email). If you choose not to
participate in these activities, your choice will in no way effect your ability to
use any other feature of this website.
If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state
law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information
is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and
copying if not protected by federal or state law.
The SBCTC website is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect any personal
information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information
requested from or volunteered by children online or by email will be treated the same
as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.
Access and correction of personal information
Many of the online services we provide allow you to manage your personal information. You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes
to your personal information you believe in error by submitting a written request
that credibly shows the error. If you believe that your personal information is being
used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us.
In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting
access or making corrections.
Public Disclosure and Public Records
In the State of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that
the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by
state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to
access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals.
Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.
As a public agency, all our information is governed by laws such as Washington’s Public
Records Act [RCW Chapter 42.56], as well as privacy laws. Information sent to SBCTC or collected through use of
this site may become a public record, and may be subject to public inspection and
copying if not otherwise protected by federal or state law.
Nondisclosure for commercial use
Pursuant to RCW 42.56.070(8), SBCTC will not give, sell, or provide access to any list of persons for any commercial
purpose. Commercial use of lists (individuals or directories including — but not limited
to — name, address, phone, email) provided at this site is prohibited.
In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act
or other law governing the disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other
applicable law will prevail.
Copyright and Open Licensing Policy
Except where noted in the SBCTC Website Terms of Use, content on this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International
License. This site also contains text, artwork, photos or other content that may be
copyrighted by others and is being used by permission.
See the SBCTC Website Terms of Use: Copyright and Open Licensing and Code of Conduct for Adopting
Content sections for appropriate use and citation guidelines.
Security
SBCTC, as developer and manager of this website, has taken several steps to safeguard
the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including but
not limited to authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. Security measures
have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day practices of the
entire SBCTC operating environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management.
This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or
other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via
SBCTC supported websites.
Disclaimer
The SBCTC website links to other websites. These include links to websites operated
by other government agencies, educational organizations, and non-profit organizations.
When you link to another site, you are no longer on the SBCTC website and this Privacy
Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy
policy of that site.
Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State
of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information
published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services
linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance
on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information
may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information
obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
The SBCTC reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time
without notice by posting such revised Privacy Notice at the SBCTC home page.
